Seven years ago,
the Yunzhou Governor's mansion
was wiped out overnight.
There were no bodies at the scene,
only bloodstains.
The court closed the case as a supernatural disturbance,
and sealed the files.
My Lord.
The head of the department explicitly ordered these files sealed.
Rumor has it there were ghosts involved in that case.
Cinnabar.
At 11:45 PM,
seven souls locked,
guided by blood jade,
never to cross into reincarnation.
Cinnabar mixed with blood
reveals itself when heated.
It's not a ghost, it's human.
Someone deliberately left clues.
Whether it is a clue or a warning
remains unknown.
Put the files away properly.
My Lord, where are you going?
To the morgue.
It is almost 11:45 PM.
If the files are a warning,
they will surely make a move tonight.
My Lord, wait for me. I will go too.
Registrar Shen.
There is only bloody water and a strange jade in the coffin.
No bodies, no bones.
I have been examining bodies for 30 years,
and have never seen anything like this.
The Criminal Investigation Department will take this case.
The patterns on this blood jade
are exactly the same
as the evidence from the Yunzhou case my father was investigating
before he disappeared.
This is not blood.
It's red phosphorus powder
mixed with rust and madder juice.
This powder has uniform granules
and extremely high purity.
It is specially supplied by the armory
for night signals.
All seven coffins are the same. The warm liquid inside
accelerated the reaction of the red phosphorus powder,
creating bubbles to simulate the illusion of boiling blood.
Someone used this method to create a bizarre scene,
covering up their true purpose
of stealing the seven corpses.
You said no one came near last night.
Did you hear any strange noises?
After 11 PM,
there were indeed thumping sounds.
It sounded like coffin lids rattling.
I thought it was a stray cat,
so I didn't dare come out to check.
Since you are the morgue keeper,
hearing strange noises from the coffins but not daring to check
is unreasonable.
I...
I just had a moment of weakness
and occasionally stole some lamp oil from the morgue to sell.
As for the coffins,
I really didn't do it!
The recurrence of the methods from the Yunzhou case seven years ago
is by no means a coincidence.
Stealing lamp oil.
But your hands and the dirt under your fingernails
are completely clean.
This shows you were only walking around normally
and didn't touch the coffins or carry heavy objects.
Stealing lamp oil is a trivial matter.
Your eagerness to confess
makes you suspicious.
You are the mortuary guard,
and seven bodies were stolen during your watch.
This is a felony.
If you don't tell the truth
and help me find the truth,
you will be exiled for 3,000 miles at least,
or beheaded at worst.
My Lord, have mercy!
I will tell the truth.
Last night at midnight,
a few people did climb over the wall.
They gave me ten taels of silver
and told me to say no one came near.
They also threatened me
that if I dared to expose them,
they would kill my whole family.
What did they look like?
They were all masked,
but the leader's
waist tag was partially exposed.
It was the style of the Imperial City Department.
I would never be mistaken.
Since the Imperial City Department is involved,
this case will be hard to investigate.
The involvement of the Imperial City Department
only shows that there's more to this case.
They set up this trap,
stole seven bodies,
and used the name of the Imperial City Department to exert pressure.
They must have an ulterior motive.
And this blood chalcedony
is the key to solving the case.
Gu of Yunzhou.
This is an old item belonging to Gu Wenyuan,
the missing Prefect of Yunzhou from seven years ago.
The body theft, the conspiracy,
and the involvement of the Imperial City Department
are all related to the disappearance of Gu Wenyuan.
This fiber was extracted from the gap of the coffin.
It has a fine texture
and is a brocade exclusively used for official uniforms.
The pattern of this brocade
is identical to the uniform of the Criminal Cases Department.
Mo'er.
Remember.
Some jade is stained with blood and tied to lives.
Is this what you were investigating back then?
Tomorrow,
we will go and meet the Director.
Someone touched the blood chalcedony.
Investigate it.